<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Ranting Penguins Rants - internet</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/internet.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2018-04-15T18:18:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Twitter banned me before #FirstTweet!</title><link href="/twitter-banned-me-before-firsttweet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-15T12:12:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-04-15T18:18:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Ranting Penguin</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-04-15:/twitter-banned-me-before-firsttweet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div id="preamble"&gt;
&lt;div class="sectionbody"&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wrote my first &lt;a href="introduction.html"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;,
figured out how I want to manage the blog and got ready to get some visitors.
Given the content I currently have, presumably not many. I want to spread my
optimism online everywhere I could so I decided to create a twitter account for …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="preamble"&gt;
&lt;div class="sectionbody"&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wrote my first &lt;a href="introduction.html"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;,
figured out how I want to manage the blog and got ready to get some visitors.
Given the content I currently have, presumably not many. I want to spread my
optimism online everywhere I could so I decided to create a twitter account for
my new identity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I setup a name, selected a username, set my profile and got ready to tweet my
first tweet. And as I started to prepare it, my newly created account was
blocked because they claim that I look like a spambot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I took some effort to customise my background, to enter some bio, didn&amp;#8217;t
follow anybody and wanted to tweet something. Right, typical bot behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can unblock my account if I enter my cell phone number. Yeah, that is exactly
what I had in mind when I setup separate identity for my ranting self - to give
everybody my personal cell number. Especially when even the real self account
doesn&amp;#8217;t have it entered anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I tried resetting password to prove I&amp;#8217;m not a bot and that I&amp;#8217;m reading e-mails,
but that was not enough, so I guess screw you twitter, no twitter for me and
I&amp;#8217;ll find some other media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;EDIT1: On the other hand I gave them a second chance and wrote an angry letter
to the support.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;EDIT2: I got automatic answer that I should enter my cell number even though I
wrote in the request that I&amp;#8217;m not willing to do so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;EDIT3: As I replied to the automatic mail, I got attention of a real person,
received apology and got my account unlocked, so everything ended well in the
end. But it looks like like that if you want to have some privacy online, it is
hard to use popular online tools.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="internet"></category><category term="twitter"></category><category term="happy-end"></category></entry><entry><title>A blog is born</title><link href="/introduction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-14T14:14:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-04-14T14:14:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Ranting Penguin</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-04-14:/introduction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div id="preamble"&gt;
&lt;div class="sectionbody"&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I tried to create a blog to rant about stuff. And first thing to rant about
is how to actually create blog. The current hype is to use static page
generators. There is like a ton of them. Most of them support Markdown, which
sucks because I prefer &lt;a href="http://asciidoc.org/"&gt;Asciidoc …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="preamble"&gt;
&lt;div class="sectionbody"&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I tried to create a blog to rant about stuff. And first thing to rant about
is how to actually create blog. The current hype is to use static page
generators. There is like a ton of them. Most of them support Markdown, which
sucks because I prefer &lt;a href="http://asciidoc.org/"&gt;Asciidoc&lt;/a&gt;. It was here first,
some claim that it is more feature complete, doesn&amp;#8217;t have tons of dialects and
syntax is more straight forward (ok the last one is subjective).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is still quite some that claim to support Asciidoc. Most of them claim to
support just Asciidoctor although I have no idea why they choose just one
specific implementation. But more importantly, most of it doesn&amp;#8217;t work well
anyway. So in the end I ended up using &lt;a href="https://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;
which finally works (after trying several generators that claimed to have
Asciidoc and that didn&amp;#8217;t worked). Pelican supports Asciidoc only through
plugin, but hey, it works and it was using this or write something on my own.
Writing it myself wouldn&amp;#8217;t be that hard, but there is too much stuff already
and it is much better and harder to reuse then to start from scratch again
(more about it in another post).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Common errors I encountered in other generators included claiming Asciidoc
support and not actually having it. Maybe the worse option was actually having
some partial support where I ended up with HTML document included in another
HTML. Including full head and full css generated by Asciidoc. So that quite
sucked, but luckily I encountered Pelican and it seems to work correctly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;So my first post actually has some happy ending. Well, I promise the next time
I will swear more and complain more about how stuff sucks to actually fulfill
the mission of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="internet"></category><category term="asciidoc"></category><category term="markdown"></category><category term="happy-end"></category></entry></feed>